Chris Castle • • • • • • • • •

109b 19th Avenue, Seattle, WA 98122 — +1 206.444.4344 — chris@crc.io

I manage analytics, dashboarding, data visualization, and big data processing products. I conceptualize, design, and manage execution. Keeping my team happy, motivated, and productive while creating delightful user experiences is what excites me; I also enjoy writing code (Ruby and Node.js currently).

EXPERIENCE

Technical Product Manager

Simply Measured - Seattle, WA - July 2012 to August 2014

- Developed, planned, and directed launch of report management product for Simply Measured's analysts, making report creation process faster and more powerful while reducing defect rate; grew and managed six-person team including engineers and a junior product manager
- · Managed four-person analyst team responsible for design and implementation of Simply Measured's product, 50+ customer-facing reports
- Adapted my role from product management generalist to product owner of Report Builder during substantial company growth (20 to 150 employees)

Product Manager, Cloud Technologies

VivaKi Nerve Center - Seattle, WA - February 2008 to July 2012

- Created product vision, prototyped (Node.js, Ruby) and directed development of multi-agency API to to allow internal development groups to access and use our managed AWS infrastructure
- Defined functionality and led development of data processing engine, processing ~1PB/week (Hadoop / AWS Elastic MapReduce)
- Collected business requirements from 1,000+ users and defined product spec for centralized marketing data storage and provisioning system

Media Technology Specialist

Client Service Engineer

Avenue A | Razorfish - Seattle, WA - October 2005 to February 2008

- · Managed feature development of online messaging, tracking, and reporting products
- Guided development of in-house web analytics tool using the Atlas ad-serving system and other web technologies, including Google Analytics and Omniture SiteCatalyst
- · Acted as Atlas ad serving technical subject matter expert
- Planned and managed ad operations for online advertising campaigns
- · Implemented pixel tracking tags on client websites

Strategy Analyst

Microsoft - Redmond, WA - March 2004 to March 2005

- · Assessed advertising and technology markets in 30 countries to determine the potential viability of MSN's business in those markets
- · Supported strategy creation for MSN's worldwide sales and marketing organization

Research Analyst

The Brattle Group - Cambridge, MA - August 2002 to March 2004

- · Created econometric models to support expert testimony for electric, telecommunications, financial, and natural gas companies
- · Taught in-house SAS (statistical analysis package) classes

EDUCATION, SKILLS, AND EXPERTISE

Colby College

Waterville, ME - August 1998 to May 2002

B.A., Economics and Mathematical Sciences with Computer Science concentration Senior Paper: Economic Consequences of Increased Internet Usage on Music Industry Sales

UX Design, Analytics, ETL, Web Analytics, Data Visualization, Digital Marketing, Online Ad Serving Technologies, Site Personalization and Measurement

Ruby, Node.js, Python, Bash, HTML/CSS/JavaScript, Linux/Unix system administration, SQL, Amazon Web Services, Hadoop, MapReduce, Git

Mountain Biking, Road Cycling, Running, Skiing, Motorcycles